我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
And I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
我让杀害母亲的凶手自食其果
I hunted down the man who killed my mother,
但我们的世界也因此出现了新的威胁
But in doing so, I opened up our world to new threats,
我是唯一来得及阻止他们的人
And I am the only one fast enough to stop them.
我叫闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on The Flash...
极速想让我死
Zoom wants me dead.
他从地球二送来的那些超能力者
The meta-humans that he's sending from earth-2,
他们可不关心挡在前边的无辜群众
they don't care how many innocent people get in the way.
我必须得走
I have to go.
我需要你告诉我可以走
I need you to tell me that it's okay.
巴里
Barry.
这就是你们的英雄吗  中城
Is this the face of your hero, central city?
说真的  你这次伤得挺重的
Seriously got your ass kicked.
我的腿没有知觉了
I can't feel my legs.
没事  我就在你旁边
All right, I got you.
我现在还不能走
I can't do it right now, all right?
-你可以的巴里  -不不  不行
- Oh, yes you can, Barry. - No, no, no.
你进步很大
You've made so much progress.
是啊  都能走六步了
Yep, six whole steps.
谁来给我奖朵小红花
Someone give me a Bozo Button.
别对自己那么苛刻
Hey, give yourself some credit.
你刚刚摔断了背
You just broke your back.
是啊  一般人怕是要瘫痪一辈子了
Yeah, a normal person would've been paralyzed the rest of his life.
我要多久才能痊愈
How long until I'm fully healed?
我一周前拍的核磁共振图
The initial MRI I took a week ago
显示出你胸腰椎接合部位的第12节胸椎
showed a complete dislocation at the T12-L1 interspace
到第一节腰椎完全错位
of the thoracolumbar junction.
但这幅是我今早拍的
But this is the MRI I took this morning.
骨骼重整
90.4%
简直不可思议  但你已经快痊愈了
It's remarkable, but you're almost completely healed.
我呼吸还是有点困难
I'm still having trouble breathing.
这是脊髓损伤后的常见现象
That's totally normal with a spinal injury.
应该很快就会好的
It should clear up soon.
我们会让你重新穿上战袍的  巴里
We're going to get you back in that suit, Barry.
很快  相信我
Real quick, trust me.
我们该拿急速怎么办
What are we gonna do about Zoom?
西斯科给他安了追踪器后  一直没动静
No sign of him since Cisco nailed him with that tranq dart.
我也没有感受到震波
And I haven't vibed since then.
或许极速不会回来了
Maybe Zoom's not coming back.
我看未必
I highly doubt that.
所以我要采取行动
Which is why I'm gonna go do something about it.
你说"采取行动"是什么意思
What do you mean, go do something about it?
我需要你们有缺口的那间房间和神速炮
I need access to your breach room and your speed cannon.
为什么
Why is that?
因为  巴里  我该回家了
Because, Barry, it's time to go home.
所以你来到我们的地球
So you show up on our Earth,
把事情搞得一团糟
you screw everything up,
现在就想拍拍屁股回家了
and now you want to go home?
听上去还真耳熟
Sounds very familiar.
再说一遍  我不是那个人
Again, that wasn't me.
我必须永远地解决掉极速
I need to take care of Zoom once and for all.
免得再有其他人丧命
Before anyone else gets killed.
你有什么计划呢
How do you plan on doing that?
我会想到办法的
I'll think of something.
拉蒙  能送我去神速炮那里吗
Ramon, if you'll escort me to the speed cannon.
不不  你不能穿过缺口
No, no, you can't go through the breach.
他可以啊
Yeah, he can.
杰伊教过我们怎么送人过去
Jay taught us how to send people.
我不是那个意思
That's not what I mean.
如果你能在你的地球打败极速
Look, if you can figure out how to stop zoom On your earth,
在这里也一样可以
you can figure out how to do it here.
我们需要你留在这里
We need you to stay here
直到我们打败极速  威尔斯博士
until we defeat Zoom, Dr. Wells.
而我需要的  斯诺博士
What I need, Dr. Snow,
是回家
is to return home.
不管你们帮不帮我  我都要回家
And I'm going to that with or without your assistance.
你在干嘛呢  哈里想走  好走不送呗
What are you doing? If Harry wants to go...Bye.
听着  不管你喜不喜欢  西斯科
Look, like it or not, Cisco,
我们需要他的帮助
we need his help.
我可不确定我们需要威尔斯出的主意
I'm not sure another plan from Wells is what we need.
对啊  他上一个"绝妙计划"差点害死巴里
Yeah, I mean, the last bright idea he had nearly got Barry killed.
我知道
I know.
但是杰伊走了
But Jay's gone,
没人比威尔斯博士更了解极速
and Dr. Wells knows Zoom better than anyone.
所以  在巴里腿脚恢复前
So until Barry is back on his feet again,
我们得留住威尔斯博士  以免极速回来
we need to keep Wells around in case Zoom returns.
凯特琳  如果他不想呆在这儿
Caitlin, if he doesn't want to be here,
让他走吧
Let him go.
不行
I can't do that.
现在还不行
Not yet.
超能力者又闹事了
Oh, snap, meta-human attack.
搞错了  只是我设的闹钟而已
Nope, nope, my bad, that is just an alert for me.
提醒事项
西斯科·拉蒙
约会之夜就在今晚
-为什么设闹钟  -就是提醒我而已
- For what? - Oh, it's just a reminder.
我一小时内有个约会
I have a date in an hour, so...
跟谁约会
Oh, with who?
跟甜美可人的肯德拉·桑德斯
With the lovely Kendra Saunders,
吉特的咖啡师
the barista at Jitters.
她做的拿铁可好喝了
Oh, she makes a mean latte.
我们应该会共进晚餐  看一场电影
I think we're gonna go out for dinner and a movie,
然后再一起吃早餐吧
and then, I don't know, maybe some breakfast.
早餐
Wait, breakfast?
为什么要一起吃早餐
Why breakfast? I don't...
是啊
Yeah...
因为  回家...
Cause, you know, you go home...
-西斯科  -然后你们就
- Cisco. - And...
-他在跟你开玩笑呢  -去吧
- He's messing with you. - Go.
是帕蒂
Patty.
-帕蒂  -我听说你还病着
- Patty, hey. - Hey. I hear you're still sick.
是啊  还病着呢
Yeah, yeah, it's a...nasty bug.
我会做非常好喝的鸡汤
Well, I make a mean chicken noodle soup from scratch.
你要是想喝的话我过会儿可以带点过来
I could bring some by later if you'd like.
谢谢  你真贴心  只是我
No, that's sweet, I just-- I'd feel terrible
我不想让你惹染上病
if you caught any of this.
而且我更喜欢吃罐头食品
Besides, I love the canned stuff.
好吧  尽量别用你的腿走路
Okay, well, try to stay off your feet.
是啊  我尽量不要走路
Oh, yeah, believe me, I am.
你真的没事吗
You sure you're okay?
感觉你遭遇了什么事
You sound like something's up.
没事  我好着呢
Yeah, no, no, no, no. I'm fine.
我只是不太舒服
I'm just not myself right now.
我希望很快能再见到你
Okay, well, I hope to see you soon,
早日康复
and, uh, feel better.
-谢谢  -再见
- Thanks. - Bye.
再见
Bye.
你还是别碰那些奶酪了
You should stay away from the cheese curds.
一吃就停不下来
They're addicting.
让我猜猜  你到这里来见我
I'm going to take a wild stab and guess that you're here
是背着你那些无所不能的队友吧
without the consent of the rest of your fabulous team.
跟你一起合作不容易
It's been difficult, having you here.
对我们来说都很艰难
For all of us.
你不用担心了
You don't have to worry about that anymore
因为我要走了
because I'm leaving.
我们能帮你救下你女儿
We can help you save your daughter.
我知道你想回去是因为这个
I know that's why you want to go home.
我来这里就是一个错误
Look, I made a big mistake coming here.
最开始我的计划是让两个闪电侠
My plan was to get the Flashes out
一起对付极速  可是我失败了
and use that help to stop Zoom, and my plan failed.
我也没有别的办法了
I don't have another plan,
只能回去独自面对极速
except to go back home and face Zoom myself.
你要是回到自己的地球
So let's say you go back to your Earth,
独自面对极速
and you fight Zoom.
他会杀了你的
He will kill you.
这样你还怎么救你女儿
And then, how does that help your daughter?
救杰西最好的办法
Look, the best way to save Jesse
就是留在这  跟我们合作
is for you to stay here, and work with us as a team.
不了
No.
让我一个人静静  我要想想
Now, please leave me alone, while I discover
哪个缺口能把我带回去
which one of these breaches is gonna get me home.
你应该感谢西斯科和斯泰因教授
You know, you're lucky Cisco and Professor Stein
因为他们暂时没有办法关掉所有的缺口
never figured out how to close all the breaches,
不然你就只能留在这里了
cause then you'd be stuck here.
等等
Wait.
我们关上了所有的缺口
We close the breaches.
但是还有一个开着
All of them, except one,
极速只能从那里进来
so Zoom only has one way to get to this world.
-尖端科研实验室的缺口  -没错
- The breach at S.T.A.R. Labs. - Exactly.
我们就在那里下个套
And then we set a trap.
里面有剑术  斗殴  拷问  复仇
It's got fencing, fighting, torture, revenge,
今日上映  《公主新娘》
巨人  怪兽  追捕和逃亡场面
giants, monsters, chases, escapes,
有真爱  有奇迹
true love, miracles, and,
同时这也是最适合约会观看的电影
it's ranked as one of the best date movies of all time.
那就看看你说的是不是真的吧
Well, let's see if that's true.
西斯科
Cisco?
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我得走了
I gotta go.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
抱歉现在临时掉链子
I am so sorry that this is happening right now.
我真的很抱歉
I am so, so sorry.
我得走了
Um, I have to go.
我会给你打电话的  好吗
I'll call you, okay?
我给你打电话  我发誓
I'll call you, I swear.
沃恩制药
好了布莱恩  给它放一晚上
Okay, Brian, let that sit overnight,
然后明早再进行化验
and then we'll assay in the morning.
肖尔医生
Dr. Shore?
您没事吧
You okay?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
你不能把它拿出来
You can't take that out of here.
我这是怎么了
What happened to me?
你是什么东西
What are you?
愚蠢的人类
Foolish Human...
我是古鲁德
I am Grodd.
帕蒂
Patty.
你找到什么了吗
What'd you find?
街上到处都是这种奇怪的毛发
Found these weird-looking hairs all over the street.
我准备拿去与资料库做个匹配
I'm gonna run 'em against the database
看看能查出些什么
and see what I can find.
这里  案子的受害者
Uh, here, our victim.
他是杰弗里·肖尔医生
His name's Dr. Jeffrey Shore.
他是沃恩制药的生物化学工程师
He's a biochemistry engineer here at Vaughan Pharmaceuticals.
这已经是两周内第二个死掉的技术员了
This is the second dead lab tech in two weeks.
这可不是巧合
That ain't a coincidence.
没错  而且跟另一个技术员一样
Yeah, and like the other tech,
他也从冷藏库中偷了一罐血清
he had just stolen a serum from their storage cooler.
-真的吗  什么血清  -叫做皮质素
- Really? What kind of serum? - It's called Cortexin.
用来治疗脑病变的
It's used to treat encephalopathy,
是一种脑内血液疾病
a blood disease in the brain.
血清不见了  但是他同事几分钟后
The serum's missing, but his colleagues found him here
发现他躺在这  死了
a couple of minutes later, dead.
他没走多远
He didn't get far.
他是因头部受到重击而死
He died from blunt force trauma to the head.
看起来伤得还不轻
Ugh, and apparently a lot of it.
没错  看看这个
Yeah, check this out.
-那是他的血吗  -撞击点
- Is that his blood? - Point of impact.
好吧
Okay.
你能把跟我说过的告诉她吗
Can you run through what you told me to her
然后看看还能发现些什么
and see if you can get anything else,
看看这些案件有没有关联点
and if the cases are linked?
没问题
Sure thing.
这是一些证物
Some of the evidence.
我等下就去找你  警探
I'll be right with you. Uh, detective?
巴里的病怎样了
How's Barry feeling?
我正要去看他呢
Oh, heading to see him right now.
他叫我给他带
He asked me to bring him
一些我自制鸡汤面
some of my homemade chicken noodle soup.
他讨厌吃罐装食品
He hates that canned stuff.
谁不是呢
Don't we all.
加速  巴里
Faster, Barry!
这就是了
There you go.
再加把劲
Push yourself!
巴里
Barry!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我现在不太好
Oh, yeah, you know, I'm not great right now.
发生了什么
What happened?
没什么  我挺好的  不用管我
It's nothing. I'm good, all right? Just forget it.
巴里
Barry.
告诉我们  我们可以帮你
Talk to us. We can help you.
不用  你帮不了我
No, you can't help me.
这次不行  抱歉了
Not this time. I'm sorry.
你理解不了的
You just-you wouldn't understand.
怎么回事  巴里
What up, Barry?
极速毁了我
Zoom destroyed me.
他向中城所有人展示了他的能力
He showed everyone in Central City what he could do,
并且我对他毫无胜算
and that I'm powerless to stop him.
他们授予了我这座城市的钥匙  乔
They gave me a key to this city, Joe.
我应该是他们的英雄
I'm supposed to be their hero.
我应该是那个能够保护他们
I'm supposed to be the guy that can protect them
不受那种邪恶侵害的人  但我失败了
from something as evil as that, and I failed
他们都看到了
in front of all of them.
现在想起闪电侠时  他们所看到的
When they think of the Flash, all they see now
只是一个没强大到能够保护他们的人
is someone not strong enough to protect them.
我没事
I'm good.
我知道我总问个不停
Oh, hey, I know I keep asking,
但是你最近有没有听过
but have you read any reports or anything recently
关于一个鸟人袭击的事件
about a Birdman attacking anywhere?
这世上没有什么鸟人  西斯科
There's no such thing as a Birdman, Cisco.
很不可思议吧  尤其是在这城里
Okay, like that's a stretch. In this city?
我知道我震波到了什么
Look, I know what I vibed.
那是一个有着又大又宽翅膀的男人
It was a man with these big, wide wings.
简直不可思议
It was crazy.
那会不会是个天使
What if it was an angel?
那是个天使
It was an angel.
凯特琳
Caitlin?
拜托  这个想法很离谱啊
Okay, come on, like that's a crazy idea.
你怎么了
What is wrong with you?
我只是不知道该怎么对待巴里
Just don't know what to do about Barry.
所有的测试都显示他没事
I mean, all the test results say he's fine,
可是就像是有什么东西束缚着他似的
but it's like there's something holding him back.
我一直想要跟他谈谈  但是没什么进展
I keep trying to talk to him, but I can't get through.
那或许我们应该找那个能做到的人
Then maybe we should get the person who can.
回家再跟你说这事吧
We can talk about that when I see you at home.
-我得接这个电话  -好的
- I gotta take this, okay? - Okay.
-再见  宝贝  -再见
- Bye, baby. - Bye.
帕蒂  怎么了
Patty, what's up?
原来这些遇害的科学家之间都有联系
Turns out our dead scientist cases are linked.
跟我说说吧
Okay, hit me.
另一个科学家偷了大量的拉斯塔姆药
Well, the other scientist stole a large quantity of a racetam drug,
通常是用来治疗服用了"迷魂"的病人
typically used to treat patients with Vertigo.
好吧  有两种药被偷了
Okay, so we got two stolen drugs,
一种是用于治疗脑部的血液病
one for blood disorders of the brain,
另一种是用于治疗"迷魂"的
and the other one for Vertigo.
有什么联系呢
What's the connection?
它们都是改善脑功能的药
Well, they are both nootropic drugs,
可以增强智力
used to enhance intelligence.
你发现的那些头发有检测结果了吗
Hey, did you get results from the hairs you found?
是的  有了
Yes, I did.
显然这种头发在另一个犯罪现场也有很多
Apparently they were all over the other crime scene too.
发现大猩猩DNA
奇怪的是  那不是人类的头发
The weird thing is, they're not human hairs.
-那是...  -是大猩猩的
- they're hairs from a... - From a gorilla.
-你怎么知道的  -帕蒂  我得挂了
- How did you know? - Patty, I gotta go.
可是...
But...
刚才凯特琳来过这里吗
Did Caitlin come through here?
没有
No.
她刚才打了我一拳  然后跑掉了
She just hit me in the face and ran away.
-古鲁德  -什么
- Grodd! - What?
-古鲁德又出现了  -凯特琳
- Grodd's back. - Caitlin.
这就是她变成那样的原因
That must be why she was acting like that.
她的大脑被控制了
She was being mind-controlled.
我一直都对我们两个世界如此相同
I'm continually amazed by the similarity
而感到惊讶
between our two worlds.
你的地球上也有会说话的大猩猩吗
You got talking gorillas on your Earth, too?
-是的  -提醒我不要去那里
- Oh, yeah. - Remind me never to go there.
拉蒙  为什么古鲁德要绑架斯诺博士
Ramon, why would this Grodd abduct Dr. Snow?
我不知道  完全不合情理
I don't know. It doesn't make any sense.
她一直都对他很好
She was always so nice to him.
他控制了两个实验室技术员的大脑
He mind-controlled two lab technicians
让他们偷了能够增强智力的化学药品
to steal chemicals that enhance intelligence.
他肯定是想从她那得到什么
He wants her for something.
他已经不在下水道里了
Well, looks like he left his bachelor pad in the sewers.
古鲁德是只很大的猩猩
Grodd's a big-ass gorilla.
他不可能在光天化日之下
He can't just walk through downtown
走到城里而不被别人发现
in the middle of the day without anybody noticing.
没错  如果有人看见过他
Right, and if there's been sightings,
或许能帮我们确定他的位置
then we might be able to approximate his location.
我给中城警局打电话
I can call CCPD.
他们可以访问举报热线
They can access the tip hotline,
把古鲁德最近的袭击资料发过来
send over files of Grodd's recent attacks.
很好
Good.
我们得把她救回来
We gotta get her back.
我们会的
We will.
巴里
Barry.
-巴里  -怎么了
- Barry! - Yeah?
你不要因为这件事自责
You can't blame yourself for this.
你也无能为力
There's nothing you could've done.
我还是没有速度
I still don't have my speed.
我们怎么能从古鲁德手里把她救回来呢
How are we supposed to save her from Grodd?
虽然你现在用不了你的腿
You may not have your legs just yet,
但你还有大脑啊
but you still got that brain.
动动脑子  帮我们想办法
Use it. Help us figure that out.
你在哪
Where are you?
凯特琳
Caitlin.
古鲁德
Grodd?
你  记得我吗
You... remember me?
凯特琳  一直  对我很好
Caitlin... always... kind...
你为什么把我带到这来
Why did you bring me here?
需要帮助
Need help.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我是怎么变成古鲁德的
How did I become Grodd?
这件事很复杂  古鲁德
That's a long story, Grodd.
粒子加速器
The dark matter
爆炸产生的暗物质
from the Particle Accelerator explosion?
就是因为这个
That's how this happened.
重复
Repeat.
Repeat?
要重复古鲁德
Need to repeat Grodd.
你是想让我创造出更多的你吗
You want me to make more like you?
我不知道该怎么做
I don't know how to do that.
去学
Learn.
下巴放低  小拳王
Keep that chin down, slugger.
爸爸
Dad.
你这主意真棒  把亨利带到这里来
That was a hell of an idea you had, bringing Henry here.
他也许失去了妈妈
Well, he may not have his mother,
但还有两个很棒的爸爸
but he's got two amazing fathers.
看来这俩爸爸对他来说缺一不可
Seemed like he needed both.
好姑娘
Good girl.
古鲁德怎么会变得有感情了
So how did Grodd become sentient?
几年前  尖端科研实验室和军方签署协议
A few years ago, S.T.A.R. Labs had this contract with the military
研究和唤醒潜在的意识读取能力
to research and awaken latent mind-reading capabilities
以帮助审讯
for interrogation purposes.
我猜古鲁德是实验对像之一
And I'm guessing Grodd is one of the test subjects?
是的  但后来威尔斯博士关停了项目
Right, but then Dr. Wells shut down the program,
我们都以为那是为了把古鲁德
and we all thought it was to save Grodd
从那些疯狂的精神控制实验中解救出来
from all the crazy mind-control experiments,
但其实是因为
but it was really so that
威尔斯博士想利用加速器爆炸
Dr. Wells could use the accelerator explosion
创造出一只680公斤的会精神控制的大猩猩
to create a 1,500-pound mind-controlling gorilla
而且还是受他操纵的
that he could manipulate.
这是什么算法
What kind of algorithm is that?
这算法可以从已知的他曾去过的地点
It's an algorithm meant to extrapolate Grodd's location
推断出古鲁德的位置
from places we know he's already been.
你好啊
Hello.
找到它了
There we have it.
没有脊髓水肿
No spinal cord edema.
也没发现亚急性出血症状
I don't see any subacute hemorrhaging.
骨头融合的也很棒  你没事了  巴里
Bone fused beautifully. You're all good, Barry.
本该让你进行物理治疗
I'd give you some physical therapy,
可你并不需要
but you don't need it.
我很高兴你在这里  爸爸
I'm really glad you're here, Dad.
我也是
Me too.
我本想给你打电话的
You know, I tried to call,
可是格拉尼特峰国家公园里面找不到电话
but you can't get a cell in Granite Peak National Park,
所以...
so...
格拉尼特峰...你怎么...
Granite Peak-- what are you--
你是独自一人去露营了吗
You went camping by yourself?
是啊  我住在帐篷里  每天都钓鱼
Yeah, yeah, I got a tent. I went fishing every day.
我都吃了好一阵子阔嘴黑鲈鱼了
I have had my fill of largemouth bass for a while.
有些时候  你需要慢下来
Sometimes you just have to slow down
才能找回前进的方向
to get back to where you want to be.
-是啊  爸爸...  -大伙们
- Yeah. Look, Dad-- - Hey, guys.
我们找到他们了
I think we've found them.
是吗
Yeah?
古鲁德肯定在这三个钟楼中的一个
Grodd has to be in one of these three bell towers.
我们之前利用城市地面的摄像头却找不到他
The only reason we couldn't find him on any cameras underneath the city before
就是因为他从住单身小屋升级到住阁楼了
is 'cause he upgraded from a bachelor pad to a penthouse,
和个土豪似的
like a baller.
好吧  我们知道了他在哪儿
Okay, so we know where he is.
但还是不知道怎么救回她
We still don't know how to get her.
-我们给你制定了一个计划  -什么计划
- We got a plan for you. - What's the plan?
派我去
We use me.
那是哈里  另一个威尔斯
That's Harry! That's the other Wells!
-巴里  -放开他
- Barry. - Let him go.
放开他
Let him go.
抱歉  抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我们在时间穹顶里又找到了一套衣服
We found another suit in the Time Vault.
-我以为他已经死了  -他确实死了
- I thought he was dead. - He's dead.
这是来自地球二的哈里森·威尔斯
This is--this is Harrison Wells from Earth-2.
-地球二  -我回头跟你解释
- Earth-2? - I'll explain later.
假如我们能让哈里说服古鲁德相信
If we can get Harry to convince Grodd
自己就是威尔斯  就是他的父亲
that he's Wells, that he's his father,
也许就能说服他放走凯特琳
maybe we can convince him to let Caitlin go.
要是出了什么差错我可帮不上忙
I'm not gonna be able to help if anything goes wrong.
我愿意冒这个险
That's a chance I'm willing to take.
我们找了两个钟楼都没找到它
Looks like we're 0-for-2 on the bell towers, huh?
我更愿意这么去想
I like to think of it more as,
现在我们知道了他们的确切位置
now we know exactly where they are.
好吧  再来试一次
Okay, let's do this again.
拿出你最好的威尔斯语调
Gimme your best Wells.
我不想再模仿威尔斯了  拉蒙
I'm not doing the Wells again, Ramon.
-我告诉过你了  -听着
- I told you-- - Look.
我做了这些防精神控制耳塞
I just made these anti-mind-control ear buds.
但它们可能会失效
They could fail,
如果真失效了  你就完了
and if they do, you're toast,
所以想活命的话  你就必须得搞定它
so you're gonna need to nail it if you want to live.
拉蒙
Ramon.
-西斯科  -西斯科
- Cisco. - Cisco.
在很多方面
In many ways,
你让我体会到了拥有儿子的感觉
you've shown me what it's like to have a son.
怎么了
What?
好了  我们再试一次
Okay, let's--let's just try it again.
这次多来一点肉麻的话  多说一点
This time, up the creep factor, like, a lot more,
而且要更加真诚一点
and make it a little more sincere.
就像你真的爱我
Like you really love me,
但却不得不杀了我
but you're gonna have to kill me anyway.
西斯科
Cisco.
在很多方面
In many ways,
你让我体会到了拥有儿子的感觉
you've shown me what it's like to have a son.
没错  就是这样  拿着吧
Yup, that's the one. Here you go.
高度机密
我们现在就去往第三个位置
Yeah, we're moving on to the third location.
收到
Copy that.
现在我们等着
Now we wait.
所以每次
So this is what it's like
你去追捕超能力者都是这样吗
every time you go after one of those meta-humans?
差不多吧
Uh, pretty much.
只是一般都是西斯科和凯特琳待在这里
Only, Cisco and Caitlin are normally the ones in here
而我才是负责跑外勤的
and I'm the one out there.
你就适合跑外勤
Well, there's no reason you shouldn't be.
爱瑞丝和我说了事情的经过
Iris showed me what happened.
和极速的斗争吗
With Zoom?
太难以接受了
That was hard to watch.
我只能想像那对你来说有多艰难
I can only imagine what that must have been like for you.
他告诉了中城的每一个人
He showed everyone in Central City
他们的英雄没能力阻止他
that their hero wasn't good enough to stop him.
看上去的确如此
Well, that's certainly what it looked like.
但真的是这样吗
Was he right?
你的身体已经复原了  巴里
Your body's healed, Barry,
而你却在这里
and yet here you are,
自怨自艾着失败的耻辱
feeling the shame of losing.
我无法阻止他
I can't stop him.
我知道  他也知道
I know it. He knows it.
而且现在这座城市里的每一个人都知道了
And now everyone in this city knows it too.
他们再也不相信我了  老爸
They don't believe in me anymore, Dad.
我因为你母亲被杀的案子出庭时
At my trial for your mother's death,
我们很多家人和朋友都来听审
a lot of our family and friends were in the courtroom.
他们听说了我对你妈妈所作的坏事
They heard awful things about what I had done to your mother.
真实与否并不重要
It didn't matter that it wasn't true.
每一天  我都能在他们脸上看到怀疑的神情
Every day, I could see it on their faces,
从我失去他们信任的那一刻
the moment when I lost them,
一直到我失去所有人的信任的时候
until everybody had stopped believing in me.
我当时的状况就是如此
Well, that was my reality.
我本来就因我没犯下的罪行而被判无期徒刑
You know, I was gonna serve a life sentence for a crime I didn't commit,
但比那更糟的是
but worse than that,
从那刻起  每一次我和人直面时
every time I looked at someone in the eye from that moment forward,
他们都会认为我在我儿子面前
they were gonna believe that I had killed the woman I loved
杀了我深爱的妻子
in front of our son.
所以没错  我很清楚被人毁掉的滋味
So yeah, I do know what it's like being destroyed.
你是怎么熬过去的
How did you get past that?
我接受了现实
I embraced it.
接受是唯一能让我继续前进的办法
Accepting it was the only way that I could move forward,
但是我知道如果能熬过这关
but I know that if I could survive that,
学会再次相信自己
and learn to believe in myself again,
那我就能熬过一切
then I could survive anything.
你知道是什么点燃了我的信念吗  巴里
You know what lit that belief in me, Barry?
是你
You.
十一岁的你  东奔西跑  坚信我
11-year-old you, running around, believing in me,
给了我希望
gave me that hope.
现在我要把希望给回你  儿子
And now I'm giving it back to you, son.
再也没有任何怪物能从我们这抢走希望
No more monsters can take that from us.
猩猩大脑与人类大脑
So, one of the main differences
最大区别之一在于
between ape and human brains
脑细胞内的白质与连通性
is the white matter and connectivity in the brain cells.
你在婴儿时期接受的化学治疗
The chemicals that you were treated with
就是为了克服这些差异
as an infant were meant to overcome those differences
引起两者的迅速增长
and cause an explosive growth of both,
在最初几年的寿命里
similar to what humans experience
经验与人类的类似
in their first few years of life.
也许这些化学物质
Maybe these chemicals can be used
可以用来复制这种增长
to duplicate that growth,
那我们就不需要粒子加速器爆炸
and then we won't need a particle accelerator explosion.
伙计
Hey, buddy.
别激动  是我
Easy, buddy. It's me.
我回来了
I'm back.
父亲  你死了
Father, you died.
不
No.
不  我没死
No, buddy, I didn't die.
我只是离开了一段时间
I just went away for a while.
非常好  威尔斯  继续说
All right, that's great, Wells, keep talking.
既然我已经回来了
But now that I'm back,
我们就不需要凯特琳了  对吗
we don't need Caitlin anymore, do we, buddy?
所以放她走吧
So you can let her go.
好吗  伙计
Come on, buddy.
让我把她带出去
Let me get her out of here.
好吗
Please.
父亲从不请求  父亲直接拿走
Father never ask. Father take.
快跑
Run.
你是谁
Who are you?
西斯科  你得进去了
Cisco, you gotta get in there, man.
西斯科  谢天谢地
Oh, Cisco, thank God.
好了  你们得快点出去
Okay, you guys gotta get out of there.
哈里被困住了  我们不能丢下他
Harry's trapped. We can't leave him here.
怎么办
What do we do?
那些药  古鲁德偷走的那些药
The drugs. The drugs that Grodd stole.
威尔斯  过量摄入那种药会使他大脑休克
Wells--an overdose of those drugs will shock his brain.
尽可能多地给他注射吧
Okay, just hit him with as much as you can.
你不是他  你不是父亲
You are not him! You are not Father!
我是父亲
I am father.
而你竟敢打父亲
And you hit father.
古鲁德
Grodd.
看着我
Look at me.
Look at me!
我绝不会抛下你不管
I would never leave you here alone.
古鲁德  我答应过你
Grodd, I made you a promise.
我对你有更远大的计划  记得吗
I have bigger plans for you. Remember?
有一天  这座城市会是你的
One day, this city will be yours.
我承诺过你
I promised you.
我打算履行我的诺言
I intend to honor that promise.
快走
Go!
走吧
Come on.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我该谢谢你救了我
Thank you for rescuing me.
我们是个团队  不是吗
Well, we're a team, right?
我很佩服  我们都是
I'm impressed. I think we all are.
我们得想办法对付古鲁德
Yeah, well, we need to do something about Grodd.
-比方说  -比方说让他永远消失
- Like what? - Like get rid of him for good.
你想杀了他
You want to kill him?
鉴于他害死了那么多人  我确实想
Considering how many people he's killed, yeah.
那不是古鲁德的错
This isn't Grodd's fault.
是威尔斯把他变成这样的
He's only like this because Wells made him this way.
没错  可他绑架你还差点害死你  凯特
Yes, but, Catie, he kidnapped you and you could have died.
你没看到我所经历的
You didn't see what I saw.
古鲁变得更聪明了
Grodd's getting smarter.
他孤独而且悲伤
He's lonely and sad.
他想要更多同类
He wan more apes like him.
什么意思  他想要孩子吗
What are you saying? He wants kids?
我确定一只会心灵控制的大猩猩
'Cause I'm pretty sure one telepathic Grape Ape
已经够这座城市受的了
is more than enough for this city.
我知道有个地方可以送他去
I know somewhere we could send him.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
在那次奇点爆炸时
When the singularity exploded
我在尖端科研实验室发现了缺口
and I discovered the breach in S.T.A.R. Labs,
我进行了相似鉴定  找出相同的缺口
I ran similar tests and discovered the same thing,
还有其他51个
51 additional breaches.
中城的缺口与之不同在于
The difference being the breaches in Central City
它们分布在城市各处
are scattered all throughout the city
然而在我的世界里  它们大部分都不是
whereas counterparts in my world most definitely are not.
你知道它们通向哪里
And you know where they lead?
我准备继续搞清楚
Well, I was in the process of figuring all that out
然而斯诺博士热切地劝我留下了
when Dr. Snow so gallantly convinced me to stay,
但如果我是对的  这个缺口就会把古鲁德
but if I am correct, this breach is gonna get Grodd
送到一个最接近家园的地方
as close to home as he's ever likely to get.
好吧  即使你是对的
Okay, even if you're right,
我们要如何引诱古鲁德穿进去
how do we bait Grodd to go through it?
我儿子会去的
My son'll do it.
是不是  闪电侠
Won't you, Flash?
古鲁德
Grodd?
凯特琳
Caitlin.
闪电侠
Flash.
古鲁德  想要凯特琳
You want Caitlin, Grodd,
你先得抓到我
you're gonna have to catch me first.
巴里准备把古鲁德引到那个缺口前吗
So Barry's gonna lure Grodd in front of the breach?
是的  一旦把他带到了指定位置
Yep, and once he gets him to the right spot,
西斯科就会用那玩意把他轰到地球二去
Cisco's gonna blast him into Earth-2 with his thingamajig.
-神速炮  -没错
- Speed cannon. - Exactly.
好吧  我发现我出狱之后
Well, things have gotten a lot more complicated
各种东西都复杂好多
since I got out of prison.
谁说不是呢
Man, you have no idea.
西斯科  马上到了  准备好了吗
Cisco, almost there. Are you ready?
我已就位
I'm in position.
你启动神速炮时
Now, once you turn on the speed cannon,
夸克物质会稳定化
the quark matter will stabilize,
把缺口拉成大约这么大
stretching the breach about so big,
所以只要在这个圈里就能成功
so anywhere within this circle will suffice.
时间刚好
Right on time.
好吧  快点
Okay, come on.
我没看到古鲁德  你们看见他了吗
I don't have eyes on Grodd. Does anyone see him?
这猩猩还真够大的
That is a big gorilla.
凯特林在哪里
Where is Caitlin?
-我的天  -站起来  巴里
- Oh, my God. - Get up, Barry.
凯特林在哪里  闪电侠
Where is Caitlin, Flash?
我在这里
Right here.
不  不  不
No. No, no, no.
快放开他  古鲁德
You need to let him go, Grodd.
闪电侠是我的敌人
Flash is my enemy.
-现在你也是我的敌人  -不
- Now you, too. - No.
他是想从你手中救出我
He was trying to save me from you.
我们当时不知道你想要什么
We didn't understand what you wanted,
但现在我们知道了
but now we do.
我可以给你你想要的  我可以给你个家
I can give you what you want. I can give you a home.
你必须得相信我
You just have to trust me.
好  他过来了
All right, here he comes.
准备好扳动开关
Ready to flip the switch.
就趁现在  巴里
Now, Barry.
火力全开
Full power.
已经全开了
It is.
巴里  你不能让古鲁德逃走
Barry, you can't let Grodd get free.
战胜你的恐惧  孩子  相信自己
Conquer your fears, son. Believe in yourself.
拜托  拜托  拜托
Come on, come on, come on.
欢迎回归  闪电侠
Welcome back, Flash.
谢谢  老兄
Thanks, bro.
难以置信穿上这身战衣的人终于做了点好事
I can't believe something good finally came from that suit.
第一次  也是最后一次
First and the last time.
那东西依然让我感到毛骨悚然
That thing still gives me the creeps.
我们应该把它毁掉
We should destroy it.
好啊  但在那之前你先看看
Let's do that, but see if you can figure out
怎样才能把这战衣放入这个戒指里
how to get it back in this ring first.
能用它应该会挺不错的
Might be nice to have something like that
省得总是老拎着个袋子跑来跑去
instead of carrying around a bag all the time.
那个我可以帮你
I can help you with that.
怎么了
What?
我对微型技术也略知一二
I know a thing or two about micro-technology.
可不是嘛  你对好多事都略知一二呢
Yeah, you know a thing or two about a lot of things.
只要他知道的能让我的孩子
Well, as long as what he knows keeps my son
和这些好人平安无事
and these good people safe,
那知道得越多越好
the more you know, the better.
哈里森  很高兴再次见到你
Pleasure to meet you, Harrison. Again.
幸会  艾伦医生
Dr. Allen.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
西斯科
Cisco.
-我们走吧  -保重
- Let's go. - Take care.
威尔斯博士  你地球上的那个地方
So, Dr. Wells, this place on your Earth
我们送古鲁德去的那里  具体是哪里
that we've sent Grodd, what is it exactly?
那是受实验影响的大猩猩们的避难所
It's a refuge where gorillas subjected to lab experiments,
像古鲁德之类
like Grodd,
可以在那里自在生活
can roam freely.
热带雨林
我知道这是最好的结果
I know it's for the best,
但我仍然感觉像是背叛了他
but I still feel like I betrayed him.
不  别那么说  你没有背叛他
No, don't say that. You didn't betray him.
你给了他更好的生活
You gave him a better life.
我还是不明白  我
I still don't understand, though, I...
为何我们地球上的缺口
Why do the breaches on our Earth
会通往你们地球上的不同地方
lead to different places on yours?
我也不知道  拉蒙
I don't know yet, Ramon,
但我知道我们必须关闭所有缺口
but I do know we have to close them all,
可我不知道要如何才能做到
and I don't know how to do that.
你不用再孤军奋战了
You don't have to do it alone anymore.
所有事都不用了
Any of it.
我们团结一致打败了古鲁德  若一直如此
Together, we defeated Grodd, and if we stay that way,
我们就会找到关闭缺口的方法
we will figure out how to close the breaches,
也可以战胜极速  找回你女儿
get Zoom, and get you your daughter back.
谢谢
Thank you.
这张照片绝对值得收藏
Oh, this one is definitely a keeper.
没错
Oh, yeah.
他本来可以用食醋和小苏打
He could've done your standard vinegar
来模拟火山爆发
and baking soda volcano,
但巴里却想用巧克力和牛轧糖
but no, Barry wanted to do a molecular structure
制作分子结构模型
of chocolate and nougat.
那可是我最爱的糖
That's my favorite candy bar.
谁会在六年级做那个啊
Who does that in the sixth grade?
真是科学怪才啊
Why, a true science nerd.
我想是有其父  必有其子
Like father, like son, I suppose.
好了  爸爸  我们该走了
All right, Dad, we should get going.
好  乔  这个我可以
Yeah. Uh, Joe, can I have...
-留着吧  -谢了
- Yeah. - Thanks.
爱瑞丝  谢谢你把我找来
Iris, thank you so much for reaching out to me.
-你能来实在是太好了  -我也是
- I am so glad you did. - Me, too.
乔  说任何话都显得苍白
Joe, there are no words, man.
谢谢你
Thanks.
我回家前要去趟实验室
All right, I'm gonna swing by my lab before I come home.
我想起来了  帕蒂是个聪明的女孩
Which reminds me--Patty? She's a smart girl.
提醒你一下  她不会相信你生病的事
She's not buying your whole sick story, FYI.
-好吧  -帕蒂
- All right. - Patty?
是你的新女友吗
Would this be a new girlfriend?
是的  算是吧
Uh, yeah, something like that, yeah.
送你去车站的路上再聊
We'll talk about it on the way to the bus station.
走吧
Come on.
-再见  -回见
- Bye. - See ya.
你没事吧
You okay?
很尴尬  我...
It's embarrassing. I--you know,
我把巴里当成自己的亲生儿来爱
I love Barry like he's my own son,
但我想起他不是我亲生的
but when I'm reminded that he isn't,
我不禁在想  如果
I start to wonder what it would've been like
会是怎样
if, you know...
爸爸  你跟你亲生儿相处会像
Dad, you would've been just as amazing
你跟我和巴里得一样棒
with your own son, just like you were with me and Barry.
我听说你在这里待了很久
I hear you've been spending a lot of time up here.
人们经常说
Well, you know what they say.
鉴证人员的执着...
When the CSI's away...
很高兴你恢复精神了
It's good to see you on your feet again.
一定是喝了罐头汤
Must've been all that canned soup you had.
或者是乔给你带来的家常菜
Or maybe the homemade stuff Joe brought you?
其实我没生病  帕蒂
It--yeah, I wasn't actually sick, Patty.
我猜到了
Yeah, I figured that out.
你为什么要对我说谎
Why did you lie to me?
我的爸爸到镇上来了
My dad was in town.
我需要花点时间陪陪他
I needed to spend some time with him.
跟我说一声不就行了
And you couldn't just tell me that?
你要了解  帕蒂
You gotta understand, Patty,
我爸爸之前以杀人罪入狱
my dad was convicted of murder.
一个人有了这样的污点
When someone's image has been tarnished like that,
世人会戴着有色眼镜看他
it's hard for some people to see past it.
你真的认为我是那种人吗
And you seriously think I'm one of those people?
不  我应该更相信你
No, I know, I should've given you more credit.
不  你应该更相信自己
No, you should've given yourself more credit.
这与你父亲无关  巴里
This isn't about your father, Barry.
而是你
This is about you.
要继续下去  我必须知道我能相信你
I need to know that I can trust you if we're gonna do this.
好吧
Okay.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
我看得出来
I can tell.
你不能总是那么聪明
You cannot always be a smart ass.
我不知道你喜欢花还是巧克力
I didn't know if you liked flowers or chocolate,
所以
so...
我两样都买了
I got you both.
我对巧克力敏感
Well, I'm allergic to chocolate,
而且我认为买花是件浪费钱的事
and I think that flowers are a waste of money.
我车上有棒棒糖
I have lollipops in my car?
西斯科  我在开玩笑
Cisco, I'm joking.
天呐
Oh, God.
我很喜欢  谢谢
This is great. Thank you.
我来这里是为了
Listen, I wanted to come over here
那晚我突然离开道歉
and say I'm sorry for bailing the other night.
我是中城警局的联络员  发生紧急情况
I--I'm a liaison with the CCPD and there was an emergency,
我必须赶过去
and I had to be there.
-中城警局  -是的
- The CCPD? - Yeah.
棒极了  你很勇敢
Wow, that's really cool. And very brave.
谢谢你
Thank you.
这个也很贴心  西斯科
And this is very, very sweet, Cisco.
这是什么
Um, what is this?
这个玩意儿
Well, see, that right there.
是数码电影放映机
That's a digital movie projector.
我把《公主新娘》都上载进去了
I loaded all of "Princess Brid" on it.
没错
That's right.
我们只需要一面墙  或者
So, all we need is a wall, or, you know,
其他能让我们继续我们未完成的
some place where we can pick up our date
约会的地方
where we left off.
如果
Well,
我们要继续未完成的...
if we're gonna pick up right where we left it...
惊讶什么  怎么了
What? What's wrong?
没什么
Nothing.
只是你的接吻技术很好
You're just a really amazing kisser.
好吧
Okay.
-我们去看《公主新娘》吧  -去...
- Let's go watch "Princess Bride"  -Let's
楼顶有面不错的墙
There's a great wall up on the roof.